Jay Coughlan

:: 250-508-7413 :: Jay.A.K.Coughlan@Gmail.com :: JayAKCoughlan.com::

Jay Coughlan is a programmer living in the Vancouver area. He has graduated from BCIT and VFS with diplomas in Computer Systems Technology and Video Game Design respectively. His years in customer service have taught him how to work well as a team and on his own, to take responsibility for his tasks, and has helped expand his problem-solving abilities. Jay has worked as a programmer on multiple projects using various programming languages and working with teams of varied specialties. He is quick to learn new tools and wants to build on his education while contributing to a great team.

Technical Skills:

- ➤ Programming Languages C#, Java, Javascript, C++, C, HTML + CSS
- System Administration Tools Windows Powershell, WMware, Jenkins, Windows Server 2008/12
- Technical Tools Unity3D, Visual Studio, Android Studio, DirectX 9, Office360, GitHub, GitFlow, Windows OS, Linux OS (Ubuntu, Kali), Mac OS

Work Experience:

Jan. 2016 - Sept. 2016

Absolute Software – Junior Systems Administrator; Vancouver, BC

- Developed and updated dashboard application
- > Worked with servers and server applications
- > Developed *Powershell* scripts to manage passwords on systems
- Compared various products for potential use

Mar. 2010 - Aug. 2015

Shell Canada – Sales Associate; Various Locations

- > Strong communication with team members
- Assisted customers with various tasks
- > Took ownership of tasks and responsibilities
- > Given the responsibility of overnight shifts and major cleaning tasks

Projects:

Cave Flier – BCIT Project:

- > Part of a four-programmer team
- First person virtual reality flight game with randomly generated obstacles and consumables
- ➤ Used *C#* and *Unity3D*
- > Three-week production cycle
- Used GoogleVR

Password Updater Script – Absolute Software Project:

- > Designed as an internal tool for Absolute Software's hosting operations team
- ➤ Used Powershell, the Powershell markup language, and PasswordState API's
- ➤ Used *C#* and *Unity3D*
- > Three-month project in between other responsibilities
- Created script to automate and manage checking password ages and generating new passwords

Moon Child:

- ➤ Worked as the lead programmer on five-person team
- Third person platformer with traditional and runner mechanics
- ➤ Used *C#* and *Unity3D*
- ➤ Four-month production cycle
- > Two levels, two separate character controllers

Education:

Jan. 2015 - Jun. 2017

B.C.I.T.

- \triangleright Completed Term 1 4; Earned a diploma in *Computer Systems Technology*
- Completed BCIT's co-op program at Absolute Software (Jan 2016-Sept. 2016)
- > Digital Processing Option- Learned about image manipulation, compression, and audio programming.
- Created a five-week game 'Skippy's Gold' for Android
- Created three-week VR game 'Cave Flier' for Google Cardboard on Android

Oct. 2011 - Oct. 2012

Vancouver Film School

- > Diploma in Game Design
- Lead programmer on my team's three-month final project, 'Moon Child'
- Learned many facets of the game design process and documentation
- Learned how to take on many roles and responsibilities

Hobbies and Interests:

Dragons, video games with friends, writing and critiquing with my writing group, fantasy novels about dragons, Pokémon, Doctor Who, dungeons and dragons, and not being killed by dragons in dungeons and dragons.

References:

Ignacio Vallejoh:

- Teammate on *Moon Child*; Game play Assistant Producer at *EA Games*, *Vancouver*
- Cell Number: (604) 442-5587
- Work Email: ignacio.ava@gmail.com

Geoff Bucar:

- ➤ Hosting Operations Manager at Absolute Software, Vancouver,
- Work Number: (604) 630-5379
- ➤ Work Email: Gbucar@Absolute.com